Guide to Anah Marie Streetman correspondence and memorabilia, 1915-1953 MS 545
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Anah Marie Streetman Correspondence and memorabilia
1915-1953
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Streetman, Anah Marie Leland
MS 545
6 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
Correspondence and memorabilia from Rice Institute student Anah Marie Leland, future wife of William McIver Streetman, regarding student life, academics and athletics first at Houston's Central High School 1915-1918, and following at Rice Institute, 1918-1922. Letters continue to 1953.
6 lin. ft. (12 boxes)
Biographical Sketch
Anah Marie Leland, daughter of Marie Angelique Schoenberger and Francis W. Leland, was born Oct. 12, 1901. She had one brother, Eaton Francis Leland. She was originally from Chicago, IL, but came to Houston in 1910 and attended Central High School and Rice Institute. She graduated Central High School in 1918 and Rice Institute in 1922 with a degree in Philosophy. While at Rice she met James Lockhart Autry III and became engaged. However, Autry died in 1922 (he graduated 1921) shortly before the wedding. Anah Marie at some point moved in with the Autry family in Courtlandt Place and became romantically involved with Autry's best friend, W.M. Streetman, an attorney with Andrews and Kurth. They became engaged and married in 1925. She was actively involved in the early cultural, civic and social activities of Houston. She died in Houston on Feb. 20, 1995 and is buried in Glenwood Cemetery.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence from and between Anah Marie Leland Streetman and others, 1917-1953, and memorabilia primarily during her high school and college years, 1916-1922. Letters detail academic and social activities at Rice and offer a glimpse at her family life and are primarily between her, W.M. Streetman and family members.
Arrangement
The material is organized into two series, Series I having three subseries.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence, 1917-1953
Series II: Memorabilia, Photographs, 1915-1918 and undated
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift from Streetman's niece, Frances Leland Fondren, on April 15, 2009.
Accruals
Future additions may be expected for this material.
Index Terms
Subjects
Social life and customs; Rice University -- History; Universities and colleges
Document Types
corrrespondence; memorabilia; photographs
Subjects (Persons)
Streetman, William McIver; Eaton, George; Leland, Anah Marie; Streetman, Anah Marie Leland; Leland, Francis W.; Schoenberger, Marie Angelique
- Series I: Correspondence, 1917-1953, 71048
  - Sub-Series A: Between Anah Marie Leland [Streetman] and William McIver Streetman, 71089
    Scope and Contents note
    Note: Anah Marie Leland Streetman had several nicknames, which help identify the correspondence: "Petty" used by her father; "City" used by her brother; "Bobby" used by husband and friends in adult life.
    - Anah Marie Leland from Wm. McIver Streetman, 1917.; 71122 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AML from WMS, 1918.; 71121 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AML from WMS, 1919.; 71120 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wm. McIver Streetman from Anah Marie Leland, 1919.; 71119 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - AML from WMS, 1920, Jan-May.; 71118 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - AML from WMS, 1920, Jun-Dec; undated.; 71117 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - WMS from AML, 1920.; 71116 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - AML from WMS, 1920, Jan-May.; 71115 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - AML from WMS, 1921, Jun-Dec; undated.; 71114 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - WMS from AML, 1921.; 71113 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - AML from WMS, 1922.; 71112 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - WMS from AML, 1922.; 71111 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - AML from WMS, 1923 Jan-May.; 71110 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - AML from WMS, 1923 June-Dec; undated.; 71109 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - WMS from AML, 1923, Jan-Apr; 71108 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - WMS from AML, 1923, May-Dec; undated.; 71107 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - AML from WMS, 1922.; 71106 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - WMS from AML, 1924.; 71105 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1927.; 71104 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - WMS from AMLS, 1927.; 71103 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1928.; 71102 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - WMS from AMLS, 1928.; 71101 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1929.; 71100 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1930.; 71099 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1931.; 71098 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1933.; 71097 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1934.; 71096 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1935.; 71095 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1936.; 71094 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1937.; 71093 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - AMLS from WMS, 1938.; 71092 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - WMS from AMLS, 1945.; 71091 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - AML from WMS, undated.; 71090 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series B: From family members, 71052
    - AMLS from F.W. Leland (father), 1922-1923.; 71088 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - AMLS from F.W. Leland (father), 197-1933,1944.; 71087 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - AMLS from Eaton Leland (brother), 1922-1929.; 71086 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - AMLS from Eaton Leland (brother), 1930-1935.; 71085 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - AMLS and WMS from various family, 71084 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Family, unidentified, undated.; 71083 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - AML from Uncle George Eaton, 1921.; 71082 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - AML from Uncle George Eaton, 1922.; 71081 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - AML from Uncle George Eaton, 1923.; 71080 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - AML from Uncle George Eaton, 1924.; 71079 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - AML from Uncle George Eaton, 1926.; 71078 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - AML from Uncle George Eaton, 1930.; 71077 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1930.; 71076 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1931.; 71075 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1932.; 71074 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1933.; 71073 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1934.; 71072 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1935.; 71071 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1936.; 71070 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1937.; 71069 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1938.; 71068 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1939.; 71067 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1940.; 71066 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, c. 1941.; 71065 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1942.; 71064 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1943.; 71063 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1944.; 71062 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1945.; 71061 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1946.; 71060 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1947.; 71059 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1948.; 71058 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1949.; 71057 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1950.; 71056 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1951.; 71055 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton,Aunt Alice, 1952.; 71054 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - AMLS from Uncle George Eaton, 1953.; 71053 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series C: From friends, 71049
    - AMLS and WMS from Autrys, 1920's.; 71051 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - AMLS from friends, various.; 71050 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Series II: Memorabilia, Photographs, 1915-1918 and undated, 71043
  - Scans of photographs, 71047 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Anah Marie Leland's Central High School, Houston, TX Scrapbook, 1915-1918.; 71046 (Box 12, Folder -)
  - Anah Marie Leland Rice Institute scrapbook, [removed to alumni scrapbooks, section 1], 1915-1918.; 71045 (Box 12, Folder -)
  - Tattler's Club pin, Rice Institute [removed to memorabilia, vault], undated.; 71044 (Box 12, Folder -)